bigdata-madesimple.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy | Big Data Made Simple

## **Our principles**

We at Big Data Made Simple – a leading tech portal in Big Data, Data Analytics, BI, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning and Data Science landscape, respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal information. This Privacy Policy document pertains to the storage, security and usage of any personal information that you provide to us through either online or other modes, via emails, texts or phone.

We do our utmost to protect our users’ privacy and ensure that we have appropriate physical and technological security measures to protect your information. Whenever you provide such information, we are legally obliged to use your information in line with all laws concerning the protection of personal information. We will use personal data only for the purpose(s) for which they were originally collected, and we will ensure personal data are securely disposed of. Our policy complies with the Data Protection Act 2018 (Act) accordingly incorporating the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

###  **What personal information do we collect and how do we use it?**

When you fill our online forms, we collect information about you, that include your name, email address, phone number, country, company and designation that you have given to us for communication. We use cookies and the technical data collected includes you internet protocol (IP) address, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.

Generally, we will only use this information within our organization to analyze users’ trends around the website and to gather demographic information about our user-base. In case of the submission of forms, we use his/her personal information to contact the him/her and provide necessary solutions. We will keep your information confidential, except where disclosure is required or permitted by law. We do not share your personal information with third parties. We do not store or process any other personal information than mentioned above and If you have any questions or concerns about the Website and/or the handling of your Personal Data, and/or to correct, amend, or delete that information where you believe that it is inaccurate, please write to us any time at contact@bigdata-madesimple.com.

###  **Cookies policy**

“Cookies” are small data files stored on a hard drive by a website to automatically collect certain information about the user. We use three main types of Cookies on our website. They are:

1\. Session Cookies: These enable you to transfer data across the different pages of our website without the need to re-enter details. All registered customers will also have access to their stored personal information.

2\. Persistent Cookies: These aid in establishing customer’s name, name of the company, email address, location (geographic and computer IP address) etc. as well as providing unique content and offers that are specific to their needs. We are also able to create an information flow that we can better understand how our website is being used and therefore how it might be improved in terms of design and layout.

3\. Third Party Cookies: Certain third parties provide cookies through this website, which are utilized for the tracking and success of advertising campaigns, the frequency with which customers are viewing specific advertisements, matching specific content to interests of customers, recording numbers of guest users visiting the website and for analysis of customers’ Internet use.

All cookies are capable of being disabled or enabled through altering the settings on your internet browser. The disabling of cookies may, however, mean some of the services that we offer may not be available.

###  **Use of re-marketing**

Re-marketing involves placing a cookie on your computer when you browse our website in order to be able to serve to you an advert for our products or services when you visit some other website. We may use a third party to provide us with re-marketing services from time to time. If so, then if you have consented to our use of cookies, you may see advertisements for our products and services on other websites.

###  **Third party advertising**

Third parties may advertise on our website. In doing so, those parties, their agents or other companies working for them may use technology that automatically collects information about you when their advertisement is displayed on our website. They may also use other technology such as cookies or JavaScript to personalise the content of, and to measure the performance of their adverts. We do not have control over these technologies or the data that these parties obtain. Accordingly, this privacy notice does not cover the information practices of these third parties.

###  **External links**

This website contains hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third-party websites have their own privacy policies, and are also likely to use cookies, and we therefore urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit, which may also be collected by cookies whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third-party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

###  **Offensive or inappropriate content**

Our website is a publishing medium. Anyone may register and then publish information about himself, herself or some other person. We attempt to moderate user generated content, but we are not always able to do so as soon as that content is published.

If you post or send offensive, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on this website, especially on the commenting section of our blogs, news etc, or otherwise engage in any disruptive behavior on this website, we may use your personal information to stop such behavior.

If you complain about any of the content on our website, we shall investigate your complaint. If we feel it is justified or if we believe the law requires us to do so, we shall remove the content while we investigate. Free speech is a fundamental right, so we have to make a judgment as to whose right will be obstructed: yours, or that of the person who posted the content that offends you. If we think your complaint is vexatious or without any basis, we shall not correspond with you about it.

###  **Changes to this policy**

We may from time to time revise this Privacy Policy. The most current version of the policy will always be found at http://crayondata.com/privacy-policy. We would also notify you should any critical changes be made to this policy either on crayondata.com or via the email associated with your account. By continuing to use our services after any changes become effective, you agree to abide by the revised Privacy Policy.

###  **Notify us**

If at any time you believe that Big Data Made Simple, its content or its users/members have not adhered to these principles, please notify us by e-mail at contact@bigdata-madesimple.com and we will use all commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and correct the problem.
